I was just getting into that.
我正聽著來勁呢
What are you doing?
你在做什么
Roast potatoes.
烤土豆啊
We're doing Christmas.
準備過圣誕吧
Christmas.
圣誕
Christmas Day, December 25th. You've heard of it?
圣誕節  12月25日  聽說過沒
No work today, so the bottle's on the table.
反正今天不用上班  酒在桌上自己拿
I know we didn't have decorations last year. But, er...
我知道去年我們沒買圣誕裝飾
I couldn't find them last year.
因為我找不到這兒哪有賣
They're only supposed to have stored essentials here.
這里的店都只賣生活必須品
I think it's kind of adorable someone thinks tinsel is essential.
竟然有人認為金銀絲織是"必須"的  真是可愛
I figured it'd be good for us to have a meal, a drink, talk...
我覺得咱倆一起吃飯  喝酒  聊天  挺好的
Good for you or me?
對你好還是對我好
Come on. What has it been, five years?
拜托  都五年了吧
How many sentences have you said to me? Three?
這么久以來你沒對我說過超過三句話
I mean, I'm exaggerating... A little.
我是有點夸張了
But, come on, there is a little bit of
但是拜托  現在簡直像
a conversational drought happening here.
對話干旱期似的
My ears need water.
我的耳朵都快渴死了
I'm not big on conversation.
我對聊天沒興趣
Practice makes perfect.
熟能生巧
Maybe I'll bore you.
我可能會讓你覺得無聊
Buddy, look, at this point,
兄弟  到了現在
being bored by anything other than snow
能對大雪以外的東西感到無聊
would be a relief.
都讓人舒心
So come on.
所以來吧
Chitchat.
隨便聊聊
Conversate... Something.
交流什么的
Come on, for me.
來吧  為我
For Christmas.
圣誕節嘛
What do you want to talk about?
你想聊什么
Why are you here?
你為什么會在這兒
No-one ends up here
混到這兒的人
without things going to total shit for them back out there.
都是在外面活得一塌糊涂的人
It's a job, not a jail.
這是工作  不是坐牢
Often one and the same thing.
這兩者時常是一個意思
So...
那么
..What went wrong for you out there?
你在外面經歷了什么
Nothing.
沒什么
Bullshit.
瞎說
It's not an interrogation!
我又不是在審你
What about you?
那你呢
An icebreaker. You're learning.
終于想聊了  有進步啊
What went to shit for you?
你遇到了什么糟糕的事
Sure you don't want that drink?
你確定不想喝點
Did you talk your way into trouble?
你是禍從口出惹上的麻煩嗎
In a roundabout way.
差不多吧
I talked to people. Made money from it.
我靠和人講話掙錢
Why? What were you?
你以前做什么的
Some sort of a Los Angeles drive-time DJ?
洛杉磯高峰期的DJ什么的嗎
I was not a DJ.
我不是DJ
More like a guru.
更像是個導師
Oh, don't say you were a spiritual guru.
你可別扯自己是個靈魂導師
I was decidedly not a spiritual guru.
我絕對不是靈魂導師
'Hello, Harry. I'm through now. How are you doing?'
哈利  我連上了  你準備得怎樣
Sorry, I'm not quite dressed yet.
抱歉  我還沒穿好衣服
'Don't worry that's why I'm here.
別擔心  我就是來幫你的
'Just show me what you're planning on wearing
讓我看看你打算穿什么
'and we'll take things from there.'
再做計劃
- How about this? - 'Doesn't work.'
-這件怎樣  -不行
'It's boring blue and you're not boring blue. Not tonight.'
藍色太悶  不適合你  今晚不行
Right. Which one of these is good?
好吧  那這些里選哪件
Like I said, white shirt with a black tie
我說了  白襯衫黑領帶
with a slim-cut grey jacket.
加一件修身灰西裝
Classic, timeless. Smart.
經典永不過時  明智之舉
I don't usually do jackets.
我平時不穿西裝
You don't usually do anything.
你平時什么都不做
And sort out that hair, because...
理理頭發  有點亂
Ok.
好的
Remember those breathing techniques we talked about, OK?
記住我和你說過的那些呼吸竅門
You're going to do fine.
你會沒事的
It's going to be fine.
會沒事的
She's cute.
她長得不錯
Yes.
是啊
Not out loud.
別說出來
Absolutely.
沒問題
You need to pick your spots when you want to talk out loud. Ok?
你想大聲說話的時候得挑個隱蔽的地方
OK. The function room is in the back.
我看看  宴會廳在后面
Trust me, if you walk in there like you belong,
相信我  如果你輕松自如地走進去
no-one's going to say anything.
沒人會找你麻煩
Ok.
好的
So what were you running, some corporate espionage outfit?
你是干什么的  商業間諜嗎
Romantic services.
約會服務
Boy meets girl thanks to...
提供現場幫助
"In-the-field assistance".
讓男孩成功約到女孩
You coached dorks whilst they cruised singles bars.
你教笨蛋怎么在單身酒吧泡妞嗎
Singles bars are depressing.
單身酒吧太壓抑了
We'd do regular bars and clubs.
我們一般選普通的酒吧和俱樂部
But at Christmas time... we'd gate-crash office parties.
但到了圣誕節  我們能闖入一些公司派對
See, there's this dynamic to Christmas work parties.
圣誕節的公司派對往往很有活力
All the attractive women have been surrounded by
那些漂亮女人一整年來
regulation office ass-clowns for the whole year,
身邊都是辦公室里那些普通的小丑
and now they want to let their hair down.
現在她們終于能放松了
According to the pop psychologist.
你是流行心理學家嗎
So I know how the mind works.
我知道人是怎么想的
Now, don't stand around like a lamppost.
別站得跟個電線桿似的
Walk over to the bar.
去吧臺前
Remember. Always move with purpose.
記住  永遠帶著目的行動
Yeah. Who's next?
還有誰
Yeah. Can I have a...?
我能要...
Three pints, a vodka Diet Coke and a shot of tequila.
三品脫啤酒  伏特加健怡可樂加一杯龍舌蘭
Yeah. Don't worry about him, all right?
別管他  好嗎
Just grab one of those empty bottles off the bar
趁著混蛋小隊長點馬尿時
while Captain Douchebag orders his piss-water.
從吧臺上拿一個空瓶子
We're just going to need it for a prop anyway.
反正我們也只是需要一件道具
Have a look around.
四周看看
See anything you like?
有看到中意的嗎
What? The blonde?
什么  那個金發妞嗎
The dark-haired girl?
那個深色頭發的嗎
Interesting choice.
這選擇很有趣
Go straight over, but focus on the blonde.
直接走過去  但把注意力放在金發美女身上
Now. Come on.
就現在  上吧
Confidence. You can do this.
要有信心  你能做到的
Hold on, just finding out who they are.
等等  我查查她們是誰
OK, bullshit opener.
閑扯個開場白
Try the horse story. At the blonde girl.
對那個金發美女說說馬的故事
Hey, so, did anyone see that guy outside riding the horse?
你們有沒有看到外面有個人騎著馬
- Did you see him? - What? A guy on a horse?
-你看到了嗎  -什么  一個騎馬的人
Yeah, like, 20 minutes ago, this guy, shirtless,
沒錯  大概20分鐘前  那人一絲不掛
- riding a horse down the high street. - Really?
-騎著一匹馬走在大路上  -真的嗎
Yeah, honestly. He, er...
千真萬確  他...
The weirdest part was that he had a bow and arrow, right?
最詭異的是他還拿著一把弓和箭
What? A real bow and arrow?
什么  真的是弓箭嗎
I swear to God. He probably did it for a bet
我對天發誓  他可能是打賭輸了
but he looked like something out of Tolkien, you know?
但他看上去好像從托爾金的小說里走出來似的
Sorry, who are you?
不好意思  你是哪位
Stall until I... until I find something.
先拖住他  等我查出點什么
I'm pretty sure I'm me.
我就是我啊
Just you're not from the office. Who do you know from here?
你不是我們辦公室的人  你在這兒認識誰
Say, "I know you." Friendly.
跟他說你認識他  語氣友善點
I know you, for one.
至少我認識你啊
Dawson.
道森
Dawson, isn't it?
道森  對吧
You met at Kath's barbecue.
你倆是在凱絲燒烤認識的
Yeah. We met at Kath's barbecue back in...
我們是在凱絲的燒烤上認識的
- June. .. - June or so. Yeah.
-六月  -大概六月的時候吧
He had a pork pie hat.
他戴了一頂平頂帽
You had a poor guy's hat.
你戴了一頂窮人帽
A pork pie hat.
平頂帽
A pork pie hat that you wore on your head.
你在你頭上戴了一頂平頂帽
He'll pretend he remembers, even though
他會假裝他記起來了
he won't actually know if he does.
盡管實際上他根本不記得
Right.
沒錯
Yeah, sorry.
不好意思
No. No, no worries. No worries.
不  沒關系的  沒關系
Crazy night.
玩瘋了
You're doing fine. Don't neglect the blonde.
你做得很好  不要忽視那個金發美女
You, I don't know.
我還不認識你
- Amy. - Amy. Hi.
-艾米  -艾米  你好
Get her to introduce you to the dark-haired girl.
讓她把你介紹給深色頭發的女子
So, are all of your friends this suspicious?
你所有的朋友戒心都這么重嗎
Nice.
漂亮
I don't think so.
不是的
This is Jennifer.
這位是詹妮弗
- Hi, Jennifer. - Hi.
-你好  詹妮弗  -你好
Now focus on Amy
繼續跟艾米聊
and we'll do that funny material that we worked on.
說說我們練過的那個段子
Anyway, this guy gets off the horse
然后  那人就從馬上下來
and he's got a backpack, right?
背著個包
The tactic, generally, was to deliberately freeze out
這個策略總得說來就是有意把
the one you were actually interested in.
你真正有興趣的那個排擠在外
For one thing you wouldn't seem needy but...
其一  你不會顯得粘人
also they would, most times, sort of lean in naturally.
大部分情況下  他們還都會參與進來
People want to be noticed.
人們渴望被人注意
They don't like to be shut out. It makes them feel invisible.
不喜歡被排除在外  會覺得沒有存在感
But this girl...
但是這個女生
this girl seemed content with being ignored.
這女孩似乎甘愿被忽略
Maybe she could smell a loser.
也許她能感覺到這人就是廢柴
No.
不是
No. She was an outsider.
不  她是個局外人
An attractive outsider.
很迷人的局外人
There's nothing more tantalising than that.
沒什么比這更撩人的了
Huh. Well, she's off. OK.
她走了  好吧
Gonna be a challenge. Don't quit.
有點難度  別放棄
Let's let our friend Amy here
讓我們的艾米
yadder on for a little while and then, uh,
再嘰歪一會兒
find an excuse to slip away.
然后找個借口開溜
They will sit outside on the balcony till,
他們會在外面陽臺
like, four in the morning...
坐到大概凌晨四點
Listen, I've just go to the little boys' room.
等等  我得去下洗手間
So just keep the party going and I'll, you know...
接著玩  我待會兒再...
Sure.
好吧
Do you actually have to go?
你真想尿啊
'Yeah, but it's not easy with you watching.'
想啊  你看著我尿不出來
I promise. I won't peek.
我保證不偷看
So you streamed everything he saw, and he trusted you with that?
你看了所有他看到的東西  他也信任你
Well...it was only me watching.
看的人就只有我一個
'Jesus, how much urine? He's pissing like a harpooned cow.'
我去  要尿多久  停不下來了還
'It's making me want to go.'
看得我都想尿了
'Well, it is!'
總算完了
OK, there's our girl. All right, Harry.
那女孩在那兒  聽好了  哈利
Your best bet is to just go over and start talking to her.
最好的辦法是直接過去跟她說話
'You just want to establish a rapport.
建立良好關系
'OK. Don't be scared of her.'
別怕她
OK, guys, any observations so far, helping our man out here?
伙計們  有什么意見可以幫他的嗎
'Here's what's interesting,
我覺得很有意思
she's pretty but no-one's hitting on her.'
她很漂亮  卻沒人跟她搭訕
'Probably means they've given up.'
可能因為他們都放棄了
'She always gives them the brush-off cos...'
她老是一副拒人千里的高冷姿態
'They're regular types, she's an outsider with zero in common.'
他們都太普通  跟她完全沒共同點
OK that's a possible 'in'.
這角度可以
Harry, engage in conversation,
哈利  跟她聊
but be cynical. Right? Cutting.
憤世嫉俗一點  懂嗎  要尖刻
'Like Bonnie and Clyde, huh?
跟邦妮和克萊德一樣
You two against the world.'
你倆對抗全世界
Confidence. Confidence.
要有自信  要有自信
Just talk to her.
直接跟她說話就好
I don't really get parties. You know?
我不是很喜歡參加派對
You just kind of turn up and it's...
每次都是來了之后
it's enforced fun, all night.
強顏歡笑一整晚
Talk about what TV shows you've fallen behind on.
聊你漏追了什么劇
Pretend to be happy.
假裝很開心
Maybe everyone else enjoys it, maybe it's just me?
可能大家都很開心吧  還是就我另類
It's definitely not just you.
肯定不只是你
Good start, now do some more outsider small talk.
開場不錯  再聊點局外人的話題
And keep looking at her. I need to gauge her reactions.
看著她  我要判斷她的反應
So I noticed you sitting alone on the edge
我發現你一個人坐在場邊
and I thought, "Hey, kindred spirit."
就想  真是同道中人
I really hate when people say "Kindred spirit", you know.
我很討厭別人說"同道中人"
And people that do that.
還有做這個手勢的人
Me too.
我也是
Yeah, I guess you don't really like parties either.
我猜你也不喜歡派對吧
The noise wrecks it for me.
聲音太吵了  我不喜歡
All the talking and talking, it never fucking stops.
大家就聊啊聊啊  永遠他媽的說個不停
OK, she curses, so should you.
好  她說粗話了  你也要說
Shit, fucking,
草  干
I fucking always totally think that it's fucking shit. You know?
我他媽的一直覺得派對就是坨屎
I can't think through all the babble.
吵得我都沒法思考
I only got through it last year because I was on drugs.
我撐過了去年的派對  是因為嗑藥了
I'm sorry, what's that? What's that?
抱歉  什么藥  什么藥
Just, like, pills, but
就是  藥丸
'they must've been pretty strong
但藥效應該挺強的
because I actually enjoyed myself.
因為我還挺嗨
That's cool.
真不錯
Don't say cool.
別說不錯
I wish I had some drugs right now.
我希望自己現在也可以來點藥
No, you don't.
不  別這么說
I'm just, I'm joking.
我開玩笑的
I don't take them any more.
我已經不嗑藥了
Say, "That's good".
說"這樣很好"
Well, that's good, because you don't...
這樣很好  因為你不需要
You don't need that shit in your system, no.
你體內不需要這種垃圾
I'd say she's a level four rock chick.
我覺得她是個四級美女
Semi-reformed. Probably respond well to spiritual conversation.
轉化得差不多了  應該很喜歡精神談話
I don't think I can face fucking weeks of that.
這事我可做不了一整周
I might bail, boys.
我可能要撤
OK, look, it's too public here.
這里太多人了
Ask if you can move someplace quieter,
問問她能不能去安靜點的地方
where you can really talk.
可以好好談談
People just want to be heard.
人都想被傾聽
That's why 90% of seduction is just listening.
所以90%的調情都是聽人說話
Or at least pulling a face like you're listening.
或者裝出一副你在聽的樣子
That works, too.
這也行
The important thing is to make them feel important.
重點是讓他們感到  自己是重要的
Like they can make you want to extinguish
他們讓你想要忽略其它的事
the rest of the world and focus on them.
只把注意力放在他們身上
Full attention.
全神貫注
Like you're not giving me now. What's wrong?
你現在就沒有全神貫注  怎么了
- That clock. - What about it?
-那個鐘  -鐘怎么了
I just, I just never noticed it before.
我以前從沒注意過它
In five years? Jesus.
五年里你都沒注意過  天吶
Anyway, the point is to stay locked in on them long enough
總之  重點是穩住他們足夠長的時間
to build a rapport.
以建立良好的關系
So, well, I would guess that either every guy in there
我想這里的每個人
has already tried to hit on you
要么就是試過和你搭訕
or maybe they find you too intimidating.
要么就是覺得你太嚇人了
Am I intimidating?
我很嚇人嗎
No, no, no, no, no. I'm just...
不  我只是
No, I just imagine that
我只是覺得
they all kind of want to get in inside your...
他們都會想要進入你的...
Head.
思想
Some of them have tried.
有些人試過
Not directly. They send messages,
沒這么直接  他們會發各種信息
or they make it so you know what they're thinking.
或者讓你覺得他們知道你在想什么
Yeah. That can't be fun.
那可不好玩
It's just tiring, you know.
其實很累人
It just doesn't end, ever.
感覺沒完沒了
- I wouldn't know, I never hit on anyone. - Really?
-我不懂  我從沒和別人搭訕過  -真的嗎
Ask her how long she's worked there.
問問她在那里工作多久了
- So, how long you worked for...- Magson Frank.
-你在這里工作多久了  -馬格森·弗蘭克
Magson Frank.
在馬格森·弗蘭克
Three years.
三年
So three Christmas parties...
那你已經過了三個圣誕派對了
This will be my last.
這將是最后一個
Oh, really? Are you leaving?
真的嗎  你要離職了
I've been planning it forever, but you know what it's like.
我計劃很久了  但是你懂的
You know you have to do it,
你知道你必須得這么做
but when it comes right down to it,
但真到了那一刻
it's hard to work up the courage.
鼓起勇氣會變得很難
You can empathize with that.
跟她說你也有同感
Yeah. It's like when you want to jump into a pool,
是啊  就像當你準備跳進游泳池的時候
and you're worried that the water's going to be cold.
你會擔心  水是不是太涼了
But you know moments after you jump in that it'll be fine.
但你明白  等你跳下去之后一切都會沒事
It's the fear of the shock that holds you back.
讓你退縮不前的是對于刺激的恐懼
Ultimately the only thing you're worried about is
說到底你唯一擔心的就是
the transition from one state to another, and that can't hurt you
從這個狀態轉換到另一個  但它不會傷到你
because it's... it's just a state change.
因為就是  改變一下狀態而已
Great stuff, kid. Almost word-for-word.
說得真好  基本字字不落了
That's exactly right, it's just a state change.
沒錯  就是改變一下狀態而已
Right. And it's frustrating cause you've always
有時也挺煩人的  因為你會聽到
got these ten voices in your head saying,
腦袋里有十個聲音在說
"don't do it"
"別這么做"
and another ten in your head saying, "do it".
另外十個聲音又說"就這么做"
Which one do you listen to?
你會聽哪個
The "do it"s.
"就這么做"
Really?
真的嗎
If you don't like it, you can just cut and run.
要是覺得不喜歡  臨時退出就好了
You know, get it over and done with.
結束一切
You're right. I will.
沒錯  我會這么做的
To changing states.
敬改變狀態
Sorry.
抱歉
'She touched his knee.'
她碰了他的膝蓋
'She touched his fucking knee!'
她居然摸了他的膝蓋
Gentlemen, gentlemen, please, please.
先生們  先生們  別激動
Harry, you're doing great.
哈利  你做得很好
Don't worry, honestly.
沒事的
Ask her if she would like another drink.
問問她想不想再來一杯
Listen. Let me get you another drink.
這樣吧  我再請你一杯
Let me think.
讓我想想
I just need the loo a sec.
我去一下洗手間
So thanks to you some gawko finally meets a girl.
也就是說多虧了你  某個廢柴終于把上妹了
It's not much of a Christmas story.
這算什么圣誕節故事
I haven't finished yet.
我還沒講完呢
Maybe he comes down her chimney.
沒準他真把她給上了呢
- I just don't feel comfortable doing this. - What?
-這么做我覺得別扭  -什么別扭
I mean she... I like her.
你看她  我喜歡她
She likes you.
她也喜歡你
It's cheating.
這是作弊啊
I'd never have even had the nerve to talk to her.
我本來連和她講話的膽子都沒有的
Aren't you glad you did?
現在你能了  難道不高興嗎
Yeah, I... Yes. Yes. But I just...
高興  當然高興  我只是
It's just a bit of a nightmare having you, you know,
只不過你這么看著實在太不舒服
all of you in my head, watching us...
你們所有人  在我腦子里看著
telling me what to do.
對我發號施令的
I just want to talk to her myself.
我只想自己和她聊一聊
And it's...it's a bit of a head-fuck.
真的讓人很混亂
I kind of want you all to go away...
我有點希望你們下線
I'm not...
我不...
- Come back to mine. - Sorry?
-去我家吧  -什么
I want you to come back to mine.
我想請你去我家
I thought about asking you,
我在想要不要請你
and a little voice said, "Do it".
然后我腦子里的聲音在說"請啊"
So I'm doing it.
我以我就說了
Say yes!
快同意啊
I want to do this.
我想請你去
It's my way of saying thanks.
這是我表達謝意的方式
- Sorry. - No.
-抱歉  -沒事
'Hole-in-one!'
一桿進洞
'On his first run! His first bloody run!'
這可是初會  初會就上壘了
- Just say yes. - Yes. Yes. Yes.
-說同意啊  -去  我當然去
I don't usually bring people back here.
我并不常帶別人來我家的
Well, I'm honoured.
我很榮幸
Come in.
進來吧
Did you watch?
你一直在看嗎
When they went back to hers and...
就是他去她家
got up to whatever they got up to...
做他們愛做的事的時候
did you carry on watching through his eyes?
你還繼續透過他的視角在觀察嗎
What do you think I am?
你以為我是什么人
Clearly, I don't know.
顯然我完全不知道
Maybe if you spoke to me more, you'd know.
沒準你多跟我聊聊  就會了解了
No. My job was done.
我不看  我的任務完成了
Of course I didn't watch.
我當然不會再看了
- Here? - Mm-hm.
-這里嗎  -是的
OK.
好
Nice place. I like the mantelpiece...
布置得很漂亮啊  我喜歡那個壁爐架
and that bird.
還有那只鳥
Kooky decor...
詭異的裝飾品
'Indicating sexual adventurousness.'
表明在性方面敢于嘗試
I'll get the drinks.
我去取飲料
- Yeah, OK. I'll just sit... - The bedroom's that way.
-好的  我就坐在  -臥室在那邊
- Yeah, OK. - I'll meet you in there.
-哦好的  -我們臥室見
OK, Harry.
好了  哈利
You're going to the moon.
你就要有艷福了
Just sooner than expected.
不過比你預想的快
- I can't...I can't do it. - This is first-time nerves.
-我  我做不到  -你第一次太緊張而已
It's all happening so suddenly.
發展得太突然了
I didn't expect this, this quickly.
我沒想到會這么快的
You just got to roll with it.
順其自然就行
I don't want you all to see, all right?
我不想讓你們看  明白嗎
- 'Oh, now he's Mr Fucking Ethics.' - Wait.
-這會兒知道非禮勿視了  -慢著
You were happy to take a window seat while others did it.
其他人做的時候你很樂意前排看戲啊
That was completely different!
性質完全不同
'I didn't hear any objections when he watched me'
那個德國妞兒給我做口活的時候
'getting sucked off by that German girl. That was a first date.'
也沒聽他有這么大意見  我那也是初會
- Look. - 'Refund.'
-聽著  -退錢退錢
Look, she's too real. This is too real.
她很真實  現在太真實了
Nothing is too real.
根本沒有"太真實"這回事
Yeah, but...
沒錯  但是
You're standing.
你怎么站著
Yeah, I...I just didn't want to be too presumptuous.
我不想太過自作主張
I need you on the bed.
我要你躺在床上
'Jesus!'
天哪
They can't fucking wait.
他們都等不及了
'Is she going to take that top off?
她那件上衣到底脫不脫
'If there's no tits. I want a discount.
要是沒奶子看  就給我打折
'They're going to have sex.
他們會上床的
You're getting the season finale in episode one.
第一集就季終了
'Yeah, but if I don't see her tits...'
好吧  可要是看不到奶子...
Will you please be patient? Jesus...have some respect.
能不能耐心點  真是服了  態度放尊重點
'Hey. Are you OK in there?'
你還好嗎
Wow. What is that?
這是什么
"Fuck them" is what it is.
是"去他們的"
A big glass of "Fuck them".
一大杯"去他們的"
Fuck who?
去誰的
Always saying what to do, half saying one thing,
總是在指手畫腳  一群人說這個
half saying another.
一群人說那個
The talk, the constant talk.
總是在說  喋喋不休
- 'This isn't good. - I'm not getting tits, am I?'
-情況不妙  -我看不到奶子了  對嗎
'I stopped taking the pills they said I should take,
我不再吃他們讓我吃的藥了
'because they dulled the sound.'
因為會影響聲音
'Always, they've spoken to me, always there, and I've had it.'
他們總會跟我說話  總在那里  我受夠了
O...okay, Harry, I think we should think about wrapping this up.
好了  哈利  差不多了  抽身吧
I was planning on drinking this tonight
我今晚本打算喝了這個
to make them stop, but I was wavering.
讓他們永遠消失  不過還在猶豫
Coward, fucking coward,
我真他媽慫
and then I met you,
后來我遇到了你
and it was fate.
命中注定
You knew what it was like and you said do it.
你知道是什么感覺  你說動手吧
So now, we're saying "Fuck it" together.
現在我們可以一起說"去他媽的"
- What's in the drink? - It doesn't matter. Wrap it up.
-里面加了什么  -無所謂  別聊了
I know you hear them too. I saw you talking to them.
我知道你也能聽到  我看見你跟他們說話了
No. They're real people, these are real people.
不  他們是真實存在的  是真人
There's no such thing as real people.
根本不存在真人這玩意
Harry, get out of there now!
哈利  快點出來
It's like a club, it's a club, where we meet girls
是一個俱樂部  能把到妹
and they talk us through...
會一步步指導我們...
- No-one understands me, either. - No.
-我也一樣沒有人理解  -不
All night, they've been watching us and there's this one guy,
整個晚上  他們都在看著我們  其中有個人
he's the leader. He's the leader.
他是頭兒  他是老大
We're the same.
我們都一樣
They are watching us. All night, they've been watching.
他們在看著我們  整個晚上  一直在看
They can see you. They can see me.
他們看得到你  也看得到我
No-one understands what that's like.
沒有人能理解那種感覺
There are a hundred who see through me,
有一百個人都能看到我
standing at their government depots, shouting what to think.
在政府的崗位上  叫喊著控制人的思想
Not any more.
到此為止了
- You too. - I don't want it.
-你也一樣  -我不需要
- It's a state change. - I don't want it.
-這是改變狀態  -我不想要
It's just a transition
這是一次改變
and soon, they won't be there and we'll be free.
很快  他們就會消失  我們就自由了
Please... Please... I don't want it.
求你了  我不想要
You do.
你想要的
You do. Sh...
你想要的  噓
She murdered him?
她殺了他
A mercy killing, she'd say.
她會說那是讓他解脫
So, when did you find out about this?
你是什么時候發現的
I mean, when did you know that this had happened?
你是什么時候知道發生了這一切的
I saw it on a newscast, I think.
大概是在新聞上看到的
Wipe and destroy everything. OK? Everything.
全部刪除  毀掉一切  明白嗎  毀掉一切
Now go.
快點
Matthew?
馬修
What's going on?
發生什么事了
What are you doing?
你在干什么
So Claire...she was my wife.
克萊爾  曾經是我妻子
She's British, you'd like her.
她是英國人  你會喜歡她的
And I'm your wife, in fact.
我是你的妻子  而且...
'Claire found out I was involved
克萊爾發現我參與了一件
'and took what you might call a dim view.'
可以說...不光彩的事
She blocked me.
她屏蔽了我
You ever been blocked?
你被屏蔽過嗎
I've had enough. Matthew, it's done.
我受夠了  馬修  結束了
- Stop it. Stop. - Not this time.
-住手  住手  -這次不行了
'It drives you crazy.
那會把人逼瘋的
Why?
為什么
'Once they hit that button, that's it, you're locked out.'
一旦按下那個按鈕  就完了  你被屏蔽了
End of conversation.
對話結束
You can't hear or speak to them.
你無法聽到他們  或是對他們說話
They can't hear or speak to you.
他們聽不到你  也無法對你說話
Every time you look at them, there's just this...anonymous shape.
每次你看他們時  只能看到  一團虛影
It usually only lasts for about, like, an hour.
那通常只會持續  大約一小時
But when they leave it going,
但如果他們一直開著
oh, shit.
該死
Price of progress, I suppose.
這就是進步的代價吧
We all got... We all got Zed-Eyes put in, right.
我們都內置了智能眼  對吧
Which is all fine and dandy until something like this happens
原本也沒事  但是一旦遇到這種事
and then it's bullshit.
那就糟糕透頂了
You can't even take them out.
你甚至都沒法取出來
Packet gravy. How British.
大雜燴肉汁  真具英式風范啊
Merry Christmas.
圣誕快樂
Now we're festive.
現在有節日氣氛了
To Christmas!
敬圣誕節
Anyway, she left me,
總之  她離開了我
took custody of Mel - that's our daughter.
拿到了梅爾的監護權  那是我們的女兒
Hence stranding me in this lovely place.
從此把我困在了這個"美好的"地方
I didn't want to be surrounded by reminders.
我可不想身邊全是能勾起回憶的東西
What?
怎么了
Did you hear that?
你剛剛聽見了嗎
Hear what?
聽見什么
Well, anyway, I'm glad we're talking.
總之  我很高興能跟你說說話
Silence can be oppressive.
沉默是很令人壓抑的
You think weird shit in a vacuum, huh?
被關在真空空間里  就會胡思亂想不是嗎
I mean, you feel better, right? Communicating?
通過交流  你感覺好些了不是嗎
Talking to me, finally?
終于肯開口跟我說話了
A little bit, maybe. Yeah.
或許是有一點吧  沒錯
You're a locked box.
你簡直就像是個密閉的盒子
I mean, that's a good thing.
那倒也是件好事
Most people are too easy to read,
大多數人都太容易解讀了
especially if you know minds.
尤其是如果你會洞察人心的話
Using party tricks to pick up girls isn't knowing minds.
利用派對伎倆去泡妞可不叫洞察人心
The picking up girls thing was a hobby.
泡妞只是個愛好而已
My job was completely different.
我真正的工作是跟這完全不同的
You'll never guess what that was.
你永遠都猜不到是什么
Marketing person?
做市場營銷的嗎
No.
不是
- Door-to-door salesman? - Please.
-上門推銷員  -得了吧
Proctologist?
直腸病醫生嗎
You're never going to get it.
你永遠都猜不到的
I'm not going to try.
我也不想猜
All right. Let's make it a game.
好吧  我們就把這當做個游戲吧
I'll describe to you...
我來跟你描述下
my day at work, and you stop me when you've guessed it.
我的日常工作  你一旦猜到就打斷我
'The extreme weather has hit sales hard this Christmas.
極端天氣造成今年圣誕季銷售情況慘淡
'Five inches of snow...'
厚達5英寸的雪...
'That's going to wreck my portfolio just when I need it.'
那會毀了我的投資的  來的真是時候
'Don't know what I'm going to do about that.
我也不知道該怎么應對了
Oh, God, more messages.
天啊  又有更多的信息
'I'll never clear this inbox.'
我看這收件箱是看不完了
Sorry. Constant bloody admin.
不好意思  總是有各種事煩我
Just time for a little snack.
你該吃點東西了
I can eat before an operation?
我可以在術前吃東西嗎
Wonders of modern science.
現代科學造就的奇跡啊
Oh, thank God. I'm starving.
謝天謝地  我都餓死了
'That toast looks burnt.
那個吐司似乎烤焦了
'Should I say something?
我該表達下不滿嗎
'Yeah, I think I'll say something.'
好吧  我覺得我還是表達下吧
All good?
沒什么問題吧
To be honest, it's not quite how I like it.
老實說  我不喜歡吃這樣的
It's a bit overdone.
有點烤焦了
Sorry.
抱歉
I'll make some more.
我再去重新做一些
'She hates me now.
她現在一定討厭我了
'How long is this going to take?'
手術過程需要多久啊
Hi, I'm Madge. I'm your anaesthetist today.
你好  我是麥琪  是你今天手術的麻醉師
'God, she's young. Hope she's qualified.
天啊  她好年輕啊  但愿她水平過關
'OK, enough. stop thinking about things that could go wrong.
好了  夠了  別再往壞處想了
'They said it's straightforward and painless.
他們說這個手術簡單又無痛
I'm just going to relax.
我好好放松就行了
'OK, just relax. Here we go.'
好的  放松  開始了
Now, just count backwards from ten.
現在從十開始倒數吧
Ten, nine, eight, seven...
十  九  八  七
six, five...
六  五
Four, three, two, one.
四  三  二  一
'I can't... I can't see.
我...我看不見了
'Where my am I?'
我在哪里
'What's that noise?'
這是什么聲音
'Why can't I see?!'
我怎么看不見了
Preparing to extract cookie.
準備提取意識副本
'What? No! Wait! I'm still awake!
什么  不要  等等  我還醒著
'Oh, my God!
我的天啊
'Oh, my God! What's happening? Excuse me? Oh, my God!'
天啊  怎么回事  請問  天啊
'That's me!
那是我
'That's me! Oh, my God! Where am I?
那是我啊  天啊  我在哪里
'I don't know what's happening!
我不知道出什么事兒了
'I don't know what's happening to me!
我不知道自己怎么了
'Hello?
喂
'Is...is anyone there?
有人嗎
Sorry.
抱歉
You're probably pretty weirded out right now, I'm guessing.
我想你現在大概非常困惑吧
It's OK, you can talk. I can hear you through this.
沒事的  你可以說話  我能通過這個聽到
- Hello. - Hi.
-你好  -嗨
I'm Matthew, I'm from Smartelligence.
我是馬修  超級人工智能公司的
My job is to explain what's happening to you as best I can.
我的工作就是盡力解釋清楚你身上發生的事
- Oh, my God! Am I dead? - No, no. You're not dead.
-老天啊  我死了嗎  -不不  你沒死
No-one's dead here.
這里沒有人死
How old did you say you we're, 30?
你多大年齡來著  30嗎
29.
29歲
29, right. So you won't remember Xerox machines?
29  好的  那你不記得影印機吧
- Do you know what a photocopier is? - What?
-你知道復印機是什么嗎  -什么
Do you know what a copy is?
你知道副本嗎
As in a copy of something? Of course I know what that is.
類似復印件嗎  我當然知道那是什么
Well, that's what you are.
嗯  你就是副本
A copy of?
什么的副本
A copy of you.
你自己的副本
- But I am me. - OK.
-但我就是我啊  -好吧
Try to blow on my face.
扇我一耳光試試
You can't, because you don't have a body.
你做不到  因為你沒有身體
Where are your fingers?
你的手指呢
Your arms, your face? Nowhere.
胳膊呢  臉呢  都沒有
Because you're code.
因為你是代碼
You're a simulated brain full of code,
你只是代碼組成的模擬大腦
stored in this little widget we call a cookie.
裝在這個我們稱之為意識存儲器的小玩意里
Why have you done this to me?
為什么要這樣對我
Ah, well... Actually you did this to you.
嗯  其實是你自己的選擇
Real you is paying for this.
真實的你付錢讓我們干的
I don't understand.
我不明白
You see, what this is, is a service.
你瞧  這是一項服務
We take a blank cookie
我們把空白存儲器
and we surgically implant it into a client's brain.
通過手術植入到客戶的大腦中
It sits there just under the skin for about a week, shadowing.
它在皮下潛伏約一周時間  進行追蹤
Soaking up the way this particular mind works.
學習特定意識的流動方式
That's why you think you're you. You are you.
所以你覺得你就是你  的確是你
But also not.
但也不算是你
Right. Well, it is a lot to process.
好了  不太容易消化
Even from inside a processor.
即便是在內部處理器里
Put me back in my body!
把我放回身體里去
That's where real you lives.
真正的你還住在那兒呢
But...
不過
What we will do though is we will give you a simulated body.
我們會給你一個虛擬的身體
We find that sometimes that helps. Are you ready?
我們發現這樣做比較好  準備好了嗎
- What? I don't understand! - Three, and two, one.
-什么  我不明白  -三  二  一
Better?
好點了嗎
This is my body.
這是我的身體
Let's not get into that again. Look around you.
不談這個話題了  你看看周圍
You've got a control room.
你有一個控制室
What's this for?
這是做什么的
That console, that's for you to control the house.
這個操作臺是用來控制房間的
I mean, real you's house.
真正的你的房子
Look. How do you like your toast?
聽著  你喜歡什么樣的烤面包
- What? - How do you like your toast?
-什么  -你喜歡什么樣的烤面包
- Underdone. Slightly underdone. - OK, perfect.
-不全焦  比全焦少烤一會  -很好
Think about how you like it,
想著你要的那種樣子
then just press the button.
按下按鈕
Which one?
哪個鍵
It doesn't matter. You already know you're making toast.
隨便  你知道要烤面包就行
The buttons are symbolic mostly anyway.
那些按鍵都只是符號
See, this is your job now.
明白了  現在這就是你的工作
You're in charge of everything here.
你控制這里的一切
The temperature, the lighting,
室溫  光線
what time the alarm clock goes off in the morning.
早上鬧鐘響的時間
If there's no food in the refrigerator.
如果冰箱里沒食物了
You... You're in charge of ordering it.
你負責訂貨
- For who? - For real you. She's paying.
-幫誰訂  -真正的你  她付錢
Where is real me?
真正的我在哪
Taking a nap. In the bedroom. Top right.
在臥室小睡  看右上方
I don't want to be in here.
我不想待在這里面
Hey! Just how you like it.
看  你喜歡烤成這樣
OK. Please stop screaming.
行了  請別叫了
Are you going to stop screaming?
你能不叫了嗎
Are you going to stop screaming? No. OK.
你能不叫了嗎  不嗎  行
I'm sorry. I had to mute you.
抱歉  我得把你靜音
Oh, sorry.
抱歉
Look. It'll be much easier if you just comply.
聽著  如果你答應就會好些
I'm not doing this.
我不干
I'm not some sort of push-button toaster monkey.
我不是幫人按烤面包鈕的替身
Would you prefer to do nothing?
那你想無所事事嗎
Well, I'm not doing this!
我不干這種事
Right. Well, nothing it is then. Let me show you what that is like.
行  那就無所事事吧  讓你試試那樣
Three weeks sound good? That should give you a taste.
三周行嗎  足夠讓你了解了
What do you mean, three weeks?
什么意思  三周
If you just wait for a... Just...
你能等一下...
What about now?
現在怎么樣
Please.
求你了
Don't do that again.
別再那么做了
Please. There's nothing to do here.
求你了  這里什么都干不了
There's nothing. There's just...
什么都沒有  什么都...
I mean, there's nothing.
什么都沒有
I did warn you.
我警告過你了
I couldn't even sleep.
我連覺都不能睡
You don't need sleep.
你不需要睡覺
Ready to go to work?
準備好工作了嗎
Oh, no, no. No, I'm not. Definitely not doing that.
不不  我不干  絕對不干那事
OK. Well, have six months.
行  再來六個月
No. Wait, wait!
不  慢著
See, the trick of it lay in breaking them
瞧  關鍵在于  要讓他們屈服
without letting them snap completely, if you get me.
而不能完全擊垮他們  你懂嗎
Too much time in solitary and they'd just wig out.
單獨待久了就會崩潰
No use to anyone, then you'd just sell them cheap
對人沒好處  只能便宜賣給
to the games industry, they'd become...
游戲廠商  他們就會成為
cannon fodder for some war thing.
戰爭游戲什么的炮灰
How are we feeling now?
現在感覺如何
Please.
求你了
Give me something to do.
給我點事情做
Ready to work?
可以工作了嗎
Yes, please. I'll do anything.
好  求求你  做什么都行
Just give me something to do, please.
求求你給我點事情做
OK.
好
Great toast, by the way.
順便說句  烤面包不錯
Is it set up?
設置好了嗎
You are all set and ready to go.
全部搞定  可以開始了
You know, as I was coming here, I saw this guy with his shirt off,
我來這里的路上  看到個人  一絲不掛
riding a horse in the middle of the street.
在大街上騎馬
How weird.
好奇怪
I swear to God.
絕對是真的
Good morning, Greta.
早上好  格萊塔
Here are today's appointments.
這是今天的行程
11am - hair with Stelios.
11點  去斯泰利奧斯理發
12.30 -
12點30
Lunch at Barney's Brassiere with Annabel.
與安娜貝爾在巴尼內衣店吃午飯
3pm - Jackanape Gallery private view, Shoreditch.
下午3點  新興文藝區杰克內普畫廊預覽
6.30 - Christmas drinks with Paolo.
6點30  和保羅參加圣誕酒會
7.30 - The Nutcracker, Royal Opera House.
7點30  皇家歌劇院  《胡桃夾子》
That's slavery.
那是奴役
A little melodramatic, isn't it?
有點夸張  是嗎
But she thought she was real.
但她認為自己是真實的
- But she wasn't. - It's barbaric.
-可她不是  -太殘忍了
It wasn't really real, so it wasn't really barbaric.
并不是真正的真實  所以也不是真正的殘忍
Again, you are not who I expected.
你又和我想的不一樣
Most people would say,
大多數人會說
"She's only made of code, she's not real. Fuck her."
"她不過是代碼  并不是真的  管她呢"
But you're empathetic.
但你卻同情她
You care about people. Don't you?
你關心別人  對嗎
You're a good man.
你是個好人
Am I?
是嗎
Based on how you've reacted to what I've said, yeah.
從你對我說的話做出的反應來看  是的
I can tell you're kind...
我看得出你很善良...
I'm not a good man.
我不是好人
A good man who's done bad things?
做了壞事的好人
You can tell me about it.
你可以和我說說
I've done stuff in my life I'm not proud of.
我曾做過讓我覺得恥辱的事情
I can't pretend I haven't.
我不能假裝我沒做過
Was it something to do with your family?
是對你的家人嗎
Wife?
妻子
Girlfriend?
女朋友
It's just us here.
這里只有你和我
Her dad never liked me.
她爸爸一直都不喜歡我
He never liked me.
從來沒喜歡過我
It's cold, isn't it? Come on.
真冷啊  走吧
- Beth. Bethany. - Dad, what now?
-貝絲  貝瑟妮  -怎么了爸爸
It gets dark about six.
6點左右天就黑了
We won't be that long!
我們不會到那么晚的
Hold on. Let me put my glove on.
等等  我把手套戴上
I think he disapproves.
我覺得他不喜歡我
He's just protective.
他只不過是關心我
He thinks I'm not good enough for you.
他覺得我配不上你
Well, I mean, he's got a point.
這也有道理
Let me take a photo of you. Stand there.
給你拍張照吧  站在那兒
I feel so awkward posing.
擺姿勢太難為情了
Come on. Be a supermodel.
來吧  別害羞
- This awkward enough for you? - It's perfect.
-這樣是不是太傻了  -美極了
Right. Ready? That's nice.
準備好了嗎  很漂亮
Hold it there.
別動
You're such a dick.
你真壞
*Black is black*
*黑就是黑*
*I want my baby back*
*我要我的寶貝回來*
*It's grey, it's grey*
*自從她離去以后*
*Since you went away Oh, oh... *
*天空就灰蒙蒙的*
We were good together, you know. We were really good together.
我們很幸福  真的很幸福
*You can blame me*
*你責怪我也罷*
*Try to shame me*
*羞辱我也罷*
*And still I'll care for you*
*我仍在乎你*
*You can run around*
*你飄忽不定也好*
*Even put me down*
*甚至辜負我*
*And still I'll be there for you.*
*我仍為你守候*
What you doing round there? Why are you all around there?
你們干什么呢  怎么都在那邊
No. No, we're going home. Come on.
別這樣  我們回家  走吧
Don't manhandle me.
別推我
I'm not going to get up if you all touch me.
你們動我我就不站起來
I'm not going to get up. I'm not going to get up.
我不站起來  我不想站起來
It's cool. It's cool.
沒關系  沒關系
Come on, Joe.
走吧  喬
I'll get your check.
我來結賬
Cheers, mate.
謝了  哥們兒
Things weren't perfection. These things never are, but...
情況并不理想  這也難免  但...
..We were really happy.
我們真的很幸福
I'll let Gita tell the story.
讓吉塔說吧
She loves boring people with our personal details.
她愛用我們的私事去煩別人
I'd been working there for about a fortnight
我在那兒工作了大概兩個禮拜
when Beth introduced the two of us, and ta-da!
貝絲介紹我們認識  然后就成了
So it's all Beth's doing.
這都是貝絲的功勞
She's the puppet-master.
她是木偶大師
What was her tip for winning me over again?
她幫你追到我的訣竅是什么來著
Not to let you hear me snore.
不讓你聽見我打鼾
We all went on this work trip once, before Gita's time.
在和吉塔在一起之前  我們有次一塊出差
I fell asleep on the coach back and snored so loud
我在后面沙發睡著了  打呼打得震天響
they all thought there was something wrong with me.
大家都以為我哪有問題
He snores like a bison.
他打呼打得像頭牛
Really, you're telling him that?
是嗎  你跟他說的嗎
Oh, another one bites the dust.
又干掉一瓶
I think she's more into him than he's into her.
她喜歡他比他喜歡她多
Don't you think?
你不覺得嗎
Is that one finished?
那瓶喝完了嗎
Yeah?
喝完了嗎
You all right?
你還好吧
- I'm tired. - You've been a bit quiet.
-我累了  -你都沒怎么說話
Just wasn't in the mood, you know?
現在沒心情
I see them all the time at work.
平常上班天天見到他們
I think I'm going to go to bed. Do you mind?
我要去休息了  你不介意的話
No, that's fine.
去睡吧
Shit
糟了
Beth?
貝絲
What?
怎么
Is this yours?
這是你的嗎
I just found it in the bin. That means pregnant.
我在垃圾桶里找到的  上面顯示懷孕了
Is it yours?
是你的嗎
Yes.
是的
I mean, that...
我是說
Christ.
老天
That's amazing, I mean... It's just...
太好了  這也...
Joe, I can't.
喬  我辦不到
A baby, a pregnancy...not now.
現在不是生孩子的時候
Not right now, I can't.
現在不行  我不行
Of course you can. My God, you'll be an amazing mum.
你行的  老天  你會是個很棒的母親
No. I'm 27, I'm not ready.
不  我才27歲  我還沒準備好
Who's ever ready?
這種事沒人準備好過
It's not...it's just too quick, OK? It's all too quick.
不  只是太快了  這一切都太突然了
We'll manage. I'll surprise you.
我們能做好的  我會出乎你意料
- You're not listening. - I can be pretty responsible
-你沒聽我說  -到了關鍵時刻
- when pushed. - Joe.
-我也是很負責的  -喬
You can put your feet up, I'll do shoulder rubs,
你可以放松一下  我來幫你揉肩
- I'll paint the house... - Joe, please.
-我會粉刷房間  -喬  拜托
- We'll be like a couple in a DIY ad... - Joe.
-就跟手工廣告里的夫妻一樣  -喬
- We'll be like a family. - I don't want it.
-我們會像一家人  -我不想要
- But it's a baby. - Joe.
-但這是個孩子  -喬
I mean, it's our baby.
這是我們的孩子啊
I know, and it's not easy for me.
我知道  這對我來說不容易
- Well, let's at least discuss this. - No. I've made up my mind.
-我們至少談談吧  -不  我決定好了
Well, I haven't.
我還沒決定好
God, look at you.
老天  瞧瞧你
You're pissed.
你喝醉了
You drank all night, Beth.
你一晚上都在喝酒  貝絲
You drank all night.
你一晚上都在喝酒
Jesus Christ, you're pregnant.
我的老天  你懷著孕啊
Yeah, well, I don't want to be.
我也不想懷
And I'm not going to be.
我也不會懷
- You're being a bitch. - Stop it.
-你這個賤人  -住嘴
You're being a cold bitch who would kill a kid.
你個弒子的冷血賤人
That's not fair.
這么說不公平
Who'd get it torn out because it doesn't suit her plans.
因為不合她意就要殺掉它
Stop or I'll block you.
住嘴  不然我就屏蔽你了
Don't you dare.
你敢
No. We can talk tomorrow, just please stop.
不  我們明天再談  求你別說了
Don't you fucking dare.
你他媽敢屏蔽我
Beth!
貝絲
Turn it off.
關掉它
Turn it off, Beth!
關掉它  貝絲
Listen to me, Beth.
聽我說  貝絲
Turn it off.
關掉它
You turn it off!
把它關掉
You turn it off, Beth!
你把它關掉  貝絲
Beth?
貝絲
Turn it... ..Off! Please.
關掉它  拜托
Turn it off.
關掉它
Beth?
貝絲
Wait!
等等
I'm sorry, I was pissed.
對不起  我當時在氣頭上
Can we just talk about this properly, please?
我們能好好談談嗎
I've said some really awful shit. Beth, I love you.
我說了些言不由衷的話  貝絲  我愛你
Listen, we can work this out.
聽著  我們能處理好的
No, Beth...
不  貝絲
Beth, please!
貝絲  求你了
Beth!
貝絲
That day, I didn't go to work.
那天  我沒去上班
I just stayed at home and...
我待在家里
..tried to work out how to make amends.
思考如何補償
But she just didn't come back.
但她再也沒回來
And thanks to the block, I couldn't...
因為屏蔽  我不能
I couldn't message her. I couldn't call her.
我不能給她發信息  也不能打電話
After a week, I was pretty desperate.
一周后  我變得非常絕望
So I just hung around outside her work,
我就到她公司附近徘徊
like a stalker.
像個跟蹤狂一樣
Tim! Gita!
蒂姆  吉塔
Have you seen Beth?
你們見到貝絲了嗎
She left.
她走了
Left. What, like...?
走了  什么意思
Handed in her notice.
她辭職了
No-one knows where she is.
沒人知道她在哪兒
Joe?
喬
- Joe! - No, leave him.
-喬  -讓他去吧
I was still hopeful that she would get in touch,
我還寄希望于她能聯系我
or at least remove the block so that I could contact her.
至少取消屏蔽  讓我能找到她
But no.
但是沒有
When there's a block, you can't even wallow properly.
屏蔽甚至讓人無法沉溺于回憶
You can't switch it off.
你關不掉
You can't take the Zed-Eyes out.
智能眼取不下來
And it doesn't just block them, it blocks every image of them.
它屏蔽的不僅是人  還有所有相關影像
So every memory I had of her was vandalised.
我和她的所有記憶都被破壞了
And then one day I'm out in town and...
有一天我到城里
..it was her.
看到了她
She was pregnant.
她懷孕了
She'd kept it.
她把孩子留下來了
Well, I just sort of lost it.
我有點失控
I just ran over and started pleading with her. Just pleading.
我跑過去求她  懇求她
Turn it off. Turn it off. Just turn it off.
關掉  關掉  把它關掉
Turn it off. Beth, turn it off.
貝絲  把它關掉  關掉
Help. Get off me!
救命  別靠近我
Some passer-by called the police.
有路人報了警
They took me down the station.
他們把我帶到警局
And that was that.
這下可好了
So, by now, the block's got legal backing.
屏蔽現在受到法律保護了
And there's a GPS so that if I go within ten metres of her,
如果我靠近她周圍十米以內
bang - I get arrested.
GPS就會報警  我會被捕
Harsh.
真殘酷
Yeah, and I've got no idea where she is.
我不知道她在哪兒
If... whether she's had the baby or not.
也不知道她把孩子生下了沒
Whether it's a boy or a girl.
是男孩還是女孩
If it's OK.
是否一切平安
I've got absolutely no way of getting in touch with her.
我沒法聯系她
Except I knew where her dad lived.
但我知道她父親的住處
So I write her a letter, this begging letter.
所以我給她寫了封信  懇求信
Laying it all out, you know, and I get no response.
寫了很多  但是沒有任何回應
So I write again...
于是我又寫了一封
..and again...
一封
..and again.
又一封
No response.
沒有任何回應
She cut you out good.
她把你完全逐出了她的生活
But there was one thing I could do.
我只有一個辦法了
I knew she spent every Christmas with him at his place,
她每年都去她父親家過圣誕節
so I knew that she would definitely be there.
她一定會去那里
So, the day before, Christmas Eve, I headed up.
平安夜前一天  我早早地去了那里
And where her dad lived was this isolated place
她父親住在窮鄉僻壤
in the back of beyond.
一個與世隔絕的地方
I'd never been up there without her.
我從沒一個人去過
It was weird being on the outside.
站在外面的感覺真奇怪
I waited there all day. Until...
我在那兒等了一整天  直到
Well, I had to take a closer look.
我必須拉近一點看
And there's her dad with our baby,
她父親和我們的孩子在一起
but I can't even see its face because...
但我看不到孩子的臉  因為
Legal blocks cover offspring too.
法律屏蔽也適用于后代
Been there.
我也有這經歷
That hurts.
很傷人
I couldn't even tell if it was a boy or a girl.
我都看不出是男孩還是女孩
I know this sounds stupid...
我知道聽起來很蠢
..but seeing something...
但能看到模糊的影像
..was better than nothing.
總比什么都看不到好
So I kept going back.
所以我每年都去
It became an annual pilgrimage.
這變成了年度的朝圣
Once a year I'd head up there and watch them from a distance.
每年我都去那兒  遠遠地看著
Watching the kid grow up, you know?
看著孩子慢慢長大
More than anything I just wanted to make some sort of contact.
我最渴望的就是取得聯系
Anything.
什么都好
So, one Christmas, kid must have been about four by now,
一個圣誕節  她當時應該4歲了
I headed up there and I took a little present with me.
我拿了份禮物過去
Just a small, stupid thing.
就是件小破玩意
For the first time, I could see she was a girl.
我第一次能看出她是個女孩
I had a daughter.
我有個女兒
So, Santa Claus...
那么  圣誕老人
..Did you try it again next year?
你來年又去了嗎
Something happened before then.
那之前出了事
'It had been a few months since
那是我去看望女兒后
'I'd been up there to look at my daughter.
過了幾個月
'I was just sat at home watching TV,
我坐在家  看電視
flipping through the channels.'
不停調臺
'..Which claimed the lives of 26 people on a quiet Wednesday morning.
在這個安靜的周三早晨奪走了26人的生命
'Passengers like Palab Ghatak,
如普通乘客帕拉布·蓋塔
'just 18, on his way to his first job interview,
年僅18歲  當時正去參加工作面試
'and Bethany Grey, a young mother
貝瑟妮·格雷  一位年輕母親
who'd only recently started...'
最近才開始...
It had been so long since I'd seen her, it was hard to imagine
我已經太久沒見過她  很難想象她的樣子
anything but that shadow in her place.
腦海里只有那個陰影
But now that the block had died with her...
但現在屏蔽隨她的死而失效
..There she was.
我看到她了
She was gone.
她死了
Sorry.
很遺憾
But there was one silver lining...
但也有一絲曙光
With the block gone.
屏蔽失效了
You'd get to see your daughter.
你可以見你女兒了
'It was almost Christmas, so I bought her this snow globe -
圣誕就要到了  所以我給她買了個雪景球
'Just a present to give her.
就是份禮物
'And I headed up to Beth's dad's.'
然后我開車去貝絲爸爸家
'And there she was.'
我看到她了
Not a silhouette.
不再是個輪廓
Real.
是真人
Hello, darling.
你好啊  親愛的
*The world*
*世人*
*May think I'm foolish*
*會笑我癡狂*
*They can't see you*
*他們看不到你*
*Like I can*
*不像我這般*
*Oh, but anyone*
*但任何一個*
*Who knows what love is*
*明白愛情滋味的人*
*Will understand*
*都能理解*
What is it, May? Would you like a drink?
怎么了  梅  要喝點什么嗎
What are you doing here?
你來做什么
Beth's dead.
貝絲死了
Do you understand?
你明白嗎
She's dead.
她死了
There's nothing for you here.
這里沒什么值得你留戀的了
Where's my daughter?
我女兒呢
What daughter?
什么女兒
This is Beth's daughter.
這是貝絲的女兒
I want to see my daughter.
我要見我女兒
May, go upstairs.
梅  上樓去
If this is about those letters...
如果你是為了那些信
..I threw them out before she saw them.
我趁她沒看到都扔掉了
She was a mess,
她當時情況很糟
she'd had to leave everything behind.
她不得不拋下一切
I want to see my daughter.
我要見我女兒
I think you should go.
我覺得你該走了
Get out of this house.
離開這房子
I want to see my daughter.
我要見我女兒
You have no daughter here!
這里沒有你女兒
It was that clock.
就是那個鐘
Then what happened?
后來呢
Tell me.
告訴我
'I just left.'
我走了
'I got in the car
我回到車里
'and I just drove.'
開始開車
'Anywhere. I don't know where.'
漫無目的
'I walked into the nearest town and I...
我走進最近的城鎮
'I slept on the street and I drank.'
睡在街上  喝醉了
'And then after a while, I don't know how long,
過了一陣  我不知道多久
'a couple of months, they picked me up.'
幾個月吧  他們抓走了我
They wanted me to talk but I couldn't talk...
他們想跟我說話  但我說不出
'..Because if I said it, it would be real.'
如果我說話了  那就是真的了
So I didn't say anything, I didn't tell them.
所以我什么都沒說  我沒告訴他們
And what about the girl?
那女孩呢
What happened to the girl?
她怎么了
I only know what they said.
我也是聽他們說的
What did they say?
他們說什么了
- What did they say? - What is this place?
-他們說什么了  -這是什么地方
- What did they say? - What do we do here?
-他們說什么了  -我們為什么在這里
Our job. The job.
我們的工作
Joe, stay with me. What did they say?
喬  聽我說  他們說什么了
What did they say, Joe?
他們說什么了  喬
That she just... she just stayed in the house.
她一直待在房子里
It was, um...
當時...
It was Christmas Eve, so she just...
當時是平安夜  所以她...
..She just stayed hidden. She didn't move.
她一直躲著  沒動地方
Then on Boxing Day she realised that no-one was going to help.
圣誕節后第一個工作日
And she gave her grandad a present that she'd made.
她給了外公一件她自己做的禮物
And she went out to go and get help.
然后就出門去找人幫忙
How far did she get?
她走了多遠
Oh, may God forgive me. God forgive me.
上帝原諒我  上帝寬恕我
So you confess?
你承認嘍
Joe?
喬
Just say it.
說吧
Just let it out.
說出來
I confess.
我承認
I knew I could do it.
我就知道我能做到
Boom! I told you I'd get it.
好了  我就說我能拿到供認
All right, I'm coming out.
我出來了
Sorry, Joe.
抱歉  喬
Well? That had to be enough...
怎么樣  這樣夠了吧
Full confession. Clear conviction.
供認不諱  定罪無疑
Well done.
干得好
Two days we pressed him and he said piss all,
我們審了他兩天  他毫不理睬
this bastard cracks him in 70 minutes.
這混蛋才用了70分鐘就撬開了他的嘴
He knows he's guilty, he needed to unload.
他明白自己有罪  他需要說出來
It wasn't really 70 minutes, not to him.
而且對他而言  并不止70分鐘
When he was first ingested, I tweaked the time preferences,
他最初被注入后  我修改了時間偏好
made it seam like five years from his perspective.
讓他覺得像過了5年
Some might say that five years with me is punishment enough.
有人會認為跟我待5年算是嚴酷的懲罰了
Wait here.
在這里等著
Mr Potter.
波特先生
Congratulations on your confession.
恭喜你供認了
That cookie we took out of your head just gave us the full story.
我們從你腦中取出的意識副本已經交待了一切
So you can keep the silent act up as long as you want.
你喜歡就繼續沉默吧
Makes no difference - you've already talked.
這毫無意義  你已經交待了
Also, Merry Christmas.
另外  圣誕快樂
So...
怎么樣
The deal?
說好的交易呢
Break a confession from him and I go free, right?
讓他招供  我就能自由  對吧
I'm the expert, you needed me...
我是專家  你們來找我幫忙的
That's one for the Home Office.
那是幫內政部的忙
We'll make good on the offer. You're free to go, Mr Trent.
我們會遵守協議的  你自由了  特倫特先生
With some caveats.
但要告誡你件事
- Caveats? - You'll be on the register.
-什么事  -你會被登記
What register?
什么登記
The one for Peeping Tom pervs.
偷窺狂登記
All I did was help some lonely guys by providing a service.
我只是幫助了一些孤獨的男人
An illegal service.
非法幫助
You also failed to report a murder -
而且你目擊兇案卻不報案
fatal poisoning, in case you've forgotten.
是毒殺  如果你忘記了的話
Kept that information from your Cookie Monster mate, didn't you?
這個你沒告訴你意識副本的其他同事  不是嗎
What does it mean, this register?
這個登記  究竟是什么
- It means you're blocked. - By who?
-你將被屏蔽  -被誰屏蔽
By everyone.
所有人
Hot chestnuts!
熱栗子
Hey, come on.
走了
Just changing the time settings.
我在修改時間設置
Cranked him up to 1,000 years a minute.
給他設了1分鐘一千年
There's a proper sentence.
這才是合適的刑期
Or do you want me to switch him off?
要我關掉嗎
No. Leave him on for Christmas.
不  留他那樣過圣誕吧
11:00
行        程
12:30
去斯泰利奧斯理發
15:00
預展
11:00
去斯泰利奧斯理發
12:30
與安娜貝爾吃午餐
18:30
與保羅吃晚餐
15:00
預展
20:30
看《胡桃夾子》
18:30
與保羅吃晚餐
12:30
與安娜貝爾吃午餐
11:00
去斯泰利奧斯理發